All India Trade Union Congress Archives
International Institute of Social History
All India Trade Union Congress Archives
1955-1965
ARCH04803
All-India Trade Union Congress
46.7 GB
International Institute of Social History Cruquiusweg 31 1019 AT Amsterdam The Netherlands
Founded on 31 October 1920 the All India Trade Union Congress (AITUC) is the oldest trade union federations in India. Papers of the AITUC covering the period 1955 to 1965.
Context
Historical Note
The All India Trade Union Congress (AITUC) is the oldest trade union federation in India, founded on 31 October 1920 in Bombay (now Mumbai). Among its founders were the renowned nationalist leader Lala Lajpat Rai ( 1865-1928), who became the first President of the AITUC, Joseph Baptista (1864-1930), N.M. Joshi (1879-1955) and Diwan Chaman Lall ( 1892-1973). The formation of the AITUC led to it being the designated the official representative of the Indian workers at the International Labour Organisation (ILO) from 1921 onwards.
The first trade unions had come into being from the late 19th century in India in jute, textile and clothing mills, and at the railways. Bombay (Mumbai), a textile manufacturing hub, had its first trade union in the shape of the Bombay Millhands Association, headed by Narayan Meghaji Lokhande (1848-1897). The incipient trade union movement had close links with social reform and anti-caste movements. Numerous strikes and other forms of protests by workers have been recorded throughout the 19th century. By the 20th century the unions extended their work to other sectors including municipal workers, the printing press, engineering goods factories, etc. The period from 1900 to 1920 also witnessed hundreds of strikes, mass meetings and processions. During these years trade unionists closed ranks with those leading the freedom struggle against colonial rulers. The unions had gone on strike in 1908 opposing the arrest of the popular freedom struggle leader Bal Gangadhar Tilak, who later on took the initiative for hosting the all-India congregation of unions to form a national centre.
Stalwarts of Indian freedom struggle like Jawahar Lal Nehru (1889-1964), Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose (1897-1945), V.V. Giri (1894-1980) also chaired sessions of the AITUC. At the beginning the AITUC had 64 affiliated unions with 140,000 members. It grew to become the largest trade union confederation in India by 1947. Well known trade unionists of the time attended sessions of the International Labour Organisation (ILO) and N.M. Joshi was a long standing member of the governing body of the ILO representing the workers.
In the late 1920s the AITUC became more radical, partly under influence of the emerging communist movement. A split followed in 1929, and the Indian Trade Union Federation (ITUF) led by former AITUC president V.V. Giri was founded. AITUC and ITUF merged again in 1939, and since then the AITUC continued playing its role as “vanguard of the working class”. The AITUC also played an important role in the struggle for independence, and was very influential in the foundation of World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU), 1945. The AITUC had a close association with the Communist Party of India (established 1925), but was never formally affiliated to it. The principle followed throughout from its foundation conference was “Free from Governments, free from Managements & Free from Political Parties”. Its membership has been given as 14.2 million in 2013, making it the third largest trade union confederation in India. The AITUC has its headquarters in New Delhi.
Custodial History
The collection presented here consists mainly of the documents of the AITUC for the period 1928-1970 that were included in one of the major digitization projects of trade union documents of "The Archives of Indian Labour", set up in 1998 as a collaborative initiative of the V.V.Giri National Labour Institute (VVGNLI) and the Association of Indian Labour Historians (AILH). In a project initiated by the Center for Modern Indian Studies (CeMIS, Göttingen, Germany) and confirmed through a memorandum of understanding (MOU) between AITUC, AILH, CeMIS and the International Institute of Social History (IISH), the extant digital collection is being standardized, and the metadata updated and published online. Subsequently the project aims to digitize and make available to the public other material and documents with the AITUC. Under the MOU mentioned above, the IISH provides long-term storage of a copy of the digital files and access to the collection through its catalog and platforms.
The project has received financial support from the "International Center for Advanced Studies: Metamorphoses of the Political (ICAS: MP)" and from the Max Weber Foundation.
Acquisition
A copy of the digital files is preserved in the digital repository of the IISH
Content and Structure
Content
This part of the archives contains correspondence, minutes, reports, resolutions and other documents related to the Congresses, General Council, Working Committee and the Secretariat of the AITUC from the period 1955-1965.
Subjects
Geographic Names
India
Persons
Dange, S.A.; Gupta, Indrajit; Gupta, Bhpesh; Shrivastava, K.G.
Organizations
Communist Party of India; World Federation of Trade Unions (WFTU)
Themes
Syndicalism/Trade unions
Material Type
Archival material
Access and Use
Access
Not restricted
Allied Material
Location of Originals
Originals held in the V.V. Giri National Labour Institute (VVGNLI, Noida, India)
Alternative Form
Documents digitized as part of the digitisation project "The Archives of Indian Labour", 1998-2020
Inventory
- AITUC Congress, 1957-1961
  - AITUC session (Prep.)
    Correspondence of AITUC centre with various affilitated trade unions related to the formation of the reception committee for and other issues related to the 27th session of AITUC in December 1965 at Indore; Letters to and from faternal unions regarding their presence in the conference; Correspondence of letters regarding the postponement of the conference and the difference of opinion with the central leadership.
    - 16-7-65 Arya Vaidya Sala Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.1
      Malyalam/ English; Kottakkal
    - 17-7-65 The Coimbatore Tea & Coffee Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.2
      English; Coimbatore
    - 23-7-65 P.L. Cashew Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.3
      English; Calicut
    - 6-11-65 Letter to General Secretary, Shiva Glass Employees Union, 1965; 2.158.4
      English; Calcutta
    - 6-11-65 Himalay Paper & Board Mills Mazdoor Union, 1965; 2.158.5
    - 6-11-65 Sen-Raleigh Employees Union, 1965; 2.158.6
      English; Asansol
    - 9-11-65 Begal Club Ltd. Employees union, 1965; 2.158.7
    - 11-11-65 Textile Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.8
      English; Parganas
    - Letter to Bengal Club Ltd, Gramophone Workers, Textile Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.9
      English; Belgharia, Calcutta
    - 11-11-65 AITUC, 1965; 2.158.10
      English; New Delhi
    - 6-11-65 Carter Pooler Employees Union, 1965; 2.158.11
    - 6-11-65 AITUC 27van Adhiveshan, Swagat Samiti, 1965; 2.158.12
      Hindi; Indore
    - 8-11-65 Chia Kaman Mazdur Union, 1965; 2.158.13
      English; Darjeeling
    - 10-11-65 Letter to Darjeeling District, Shiva Glass, B.S. & Plywood, Kamla Engg., Himalay Paper, Sen-Raleigh Employees Union, 1965; 2.158.14
      English; Darjeeling, Calcutta, Asansol
    - 10-11-65 AITUC 27th Adiveshan Swagat Samiti, 1965; 2.158.15
      English; Indore
    - 12-11-65 Letter to Carter Pooler, Calcutta Lower Grade Employees Union, 1965; 2.158.16
    - 15-11-65 Burdwan Rickshaw Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.17
      English; Burdwan
    - Express Com. S S Mirajkar, 1965; 2.158.18
      English
    - 12-11-65 Gramophone Workers Welfare Union, 1965; 2.158.19
    - 16-11-65 Sadhana Ausadhalaya Factory Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.20
    - 16-11-65 Heroes Engineering Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.21
    - 13-11-65 Glass Blowers Union, 1965; 2.158.22
    - 16-11-65 Hind Mazdur Panchayat, 1965; 2.158.23
      English; Bombay
    - 20-11-65 Letter to Com. Dange, 3702 24/11/65, 1965; 2.158.24
      English; Bornala
    - 22-11-65 S. Krishnamurti, 3723 24/11/65, 1965; 2.158.25
      English; Madras
    - 20-11-65 Anadi Das, 3721 24/11/65, 1965; 2.158.26
    - 23-11-65 The Gen. Sec. 3699 24/11/65, 1965; 2.158.27
      English; Delhi
    - 24-11-65 Sheet Metal Workers Union, 1965; 2.158.28
    - 24-11-65 Letter to Com. Mahendra Sen, 1965; 2.158.29
    - 25-11-65 Circular, AITUC Session postponed, 1965; 2.158.30
    - 14-12-65 Union Marocaine DU Travail, 1965; 2.158.31
    - 22-12-65 Letter to The Secretariat, Telegram, 1965; 2.158.32
      English; France
    - 9-12-65 International Longshoremen's & Warehousemen's Union, 1965; 2.158.33
    - 22-12-65 Mr. Harry Bridges, 1965; 2.158.34
      English; San Francisco
    - Dear Friend, The 27th session.., 1965; 2.158.35
  - Documents and Resolutions of AITUC Conference of 29th Dec, 1957
    Documents and Resolutions of AITUC Conference of 1957: Resolutions paased in the conference on Social Security; Wages and Bonus, Peace and the banning of Weapons of Mass Destruction; Goa Liberation, Colonialism, Food Crisis, Tripartite Agreement and code of discipline, Workers' Unity, Supreme Court and tthe Amendment of the constitution, Labour laws, Samyukta Maharashtra and Maha Gujrat agitations. Resoluion on various unions like Oil Mill Workers' Union, Hotel Workers' Union, Plantation, Mine, Textile and Mica workers' demands and recent agitations.
    - Draft on Social Security, 1957; 2.6.1
    - Draft on Wages & Bonus, 1957; 2.6.2
    - Draft on Resolution on Peace & The banning of Weapons of Mass Destruction, 1957; 2.6.3
    - Draft on Algeria, 1957; 2.6.4
    - Draft on Indonesia, 1957; 2.6.5
    - Draft on Against Cononialism, 1957; 2.6.6
    - Draft on Goa, 1957; 2.6.7
    - On Food Crisis, 1957; 2.6.8
    - On Tripartite Agreements and Code of Discipline, 1957; 2.6.9
    - Draft Resolution on Unity, 1957; 2.6.10
    - The Supreme Court & Amendment to the Constitution, 1957; 2.6.11
    - Draft on Labour Laws, Awards & Their Enforcement & Proper Implementation, 1957; 2.6.12
    - Draft Resolution on Samyukta Maharashtra & Maha Gujerath, 1957; 2.6.13
    - Kannitta & Oil Mill Workers Union, Resolution, 1957; 2.6.14
      English; Alleppey
    - Resolution on Behalf of Hotel Workers Union, Character of Demands, 1957; 2.6.15
      English; Agra
    - 16-12-57 Letter to Gen. Sec., The Plantation Labour Assotiation, 1957; 2.6.16
    - Draft Resolution on Plantation, 1957; 2.6.17
    - Draft Resolution on Miles, 1957; 2.6.18
    - 17-12-57 Resolution, C-11, 1957; 2.6.19
      Tamil
    - 14-12-57 Madras City Hotel Workers Assotiation, 1957; 2.6.20
    - 10-12-57 Andhra Pradesh Mica Workers Union, 1957; 2.6.21
      English; Andhra Pradesh
    - The Textile Labour Union, Session mein Rajisthan ke liye prastav, 1957; 2.6.22
      Hindi; Gujrat
    - The Coimbatore Tea Coffee Workers Union, 1957; 2.6.23
      Tamil; Coimbatore
  - 26th Session of AITUC- Reception Committee
    Correspondence with various trade unions affiliated to the AITUC and AITUC Centre regarding the organisation of the 26th sessions of AITUC at Coimbatore.
    - 18-1-61 Letter to K.G., 1961; 2.14.1
    - 1-1-61 Swadhinata, 1961; 2.14.2
    - 2-1-61 Kozhikode District Trade Union Council of AITUC, 1961; 2.14.3
      English; Kozhikode
    - 20-12-60 Letter to Com. K.G. Srivastava, 1960; 2.14.4
    - 20-12-60 Dear Com. NKK, 1960; 2.14.5
    - 19-12-60 Dear Com. Sundaram, 1960; 2.14.6
    - 16-12-60 Letter to Comrade K.G., 1960; 2.14.7
    - 9-12-60 TUC, Dear Comrade, 1960; 2.14.8
    - 15-12-60 Letter to My Dear KG, 1960; 2.14.9
    - 15-12-60, 3831, 1960; 2.14.10
    - 17-12-60 Letter to Dear Com. T.R.G., 1960; 2.14.11
    - 16-12-60 Letter to K.G.S. on Postcard, 1960; 2.14.12
    - 13-12-60 Letter to Dear Com. TRG, 1960; 2.14.13
    - 10-12-60 Letter to Dear Comrade KGS., 1960-61; 2.14.14
    - 11-12-60 Letter to K.G. Srivastava on Postcard, 1960; 2.14.15
    - 26th Session, 1960; 2.14.16
    - 7-12-60 Letter to Dear Co. K.G., 1960; 2.14.17
    - 12-1-61 26th Session, 1961; 2.14.18
    - 5-12-60 Letter to Dear Parvathi, 1960; 2.14.19
    - Coimbatore where…, 1960-61; 2.14.20
    - Tamilnad Trade Union Congress, 1960; 2.14.21
    - 17-11-60 Letter to Dear Chaudhari, 1960; 2.14.22
    - 14-11-60 Gen. Engg. Employees Union, I.D. Khan, 1960; 2.14.23
    - 7-11-60 The Coimbatore District Mill Workers Union, 1960; 2.14.24
    - 12-11-60 Working Committee meeting - coimbatore- jauary 4,1960, 2.14.25
    - 18-10-60 Letter to Dear Com. TRG, 1960; 2.14.26
    - Letter to dear com. KGS, The Sec., 1960-61; 2.14.27
    - 15-10-60 Dear Comrade, The Secretary, 1960; 2.14.28
    - 14-7-60 Telegram, Prepared Hold Annual.., 1960; 2.14.29
    - 14-9-60 Letter to Dear Comrade, Gen. sec, 1960; 2.14.30
    - 4-7-60 Personal, N.K. Krishan, 1960; 2.14.31
    - 29-6-60 Letter to Dear NKK, Conf, 1960; 2.14.32
    - 25-6-60 Letter to Dear Com. NKK, Conference, 1960; 2.14.33
    - 24-6-60 Wire Immediate Confirmation, 1960; 2.14.34
    - 10-1-61 Invitation for the presentation, 1960-61; 2.14.35
- General Council (AITUC), 1960
  - Working Committee Meeting (Circulars)
    New Year Greeting of AITUC; Correrspondence of South Arcot District Hotel Workers' Union with AITUC centre regarding affiliation; Circular and documents of AITUC related to the working committee meeting of AITUC in Delhi, 1960.
    - 6-1-61 Letter to The Secretary, AITUC, 1961; 3.34.1
      English; Tirupapuliyur
    - New Year Greeting, 1961; 3.34.2
      English / Hindi
    - 13-7-1960 Letter to All Members of the Working Committee of the AITUC & Special Invitees, 3.34.3
    - 29-7-60 Letter to All Members of the Working Committee & Special Invitees, 1960; 3.34.4
    - 20-7-60 Letter to All Members of the Working Committee of the AITUC, 1960; 3.34.5
    - AITUC Working Committee - AGENDA, 1959; 3.34.6
    - 14-1-60 Letter to All Members of the Working Committee, 1960; 3.34.7
    - 14-1-60 Letter to All Members of the General Council, 1960; 3.34.8
  - Correspondence with State Govt.
    Request to AITUC to prepare panel of Arbtrators for the labour Committee by the Labour minstry; Notification of Government of UP for implementing Central Cotton Textile Wage Board published in the Labour Gazettee; Correspondence related to the implementation of Cotton Textile Wage Board in Andhra Pradesh; Papers related to the Master Plan for Industrialisation of the Bombay State.
    - 16-12-60 letter to The General Secretary, AITUE, 1960; 3.38.1
      English; Gujrat
    - 19-10-60 Letter to Shri M D Shanbagh, Under Secrt. to the Govt. of Maharashtra, 1960; 3.38.2
    - 29-7-60 Govt. of Uttar Pradesh Labour (A) Department, Notification, 1960; 3.38.3
      English; Lucknow
    - 1-10-60 Letter to Shri H.N.Bahuguna, Deputy Minister of Labour, Govt. of U.P., 1960; 3.38.4
    - 28-6-60 Procedings of the Tripartite Labour Confrence Held at the State Central Library Hall, 1960; 3.38.5
      English; Assam
    - 8-6-60 Letter to the Labour Minister, Govt. of U.P., 1960; 3.38.6
      English; Uttar Pradesh
    - 20-5-60 Letter to The Director, Bombay Labour Institute, 1960; 3.38.7
    - 18-4-60 Letter to the General Secretary, AITUC-Rajasthan, 1960; 3.38.8
    - 15-4-60 Letter to Mr. Raj Bahadur Gour, M.P. AITUC, 1960; 3.38.9
      English; Hyderabad
    - 15-4-60 Indian Posts and Telegraphs Department, 1960; 3.38.10
    - 12-4-60 Letter to The Shri Yeshwantrao Chavan, C.M. Govt. of Bombay, 1960; 3.38.11
    - 23-3-60 Letter to Shri N. ramchandra Reddy, Labour Minister, Govt. of Andhra Pradesh, 1960; 3.38.12
    - 16-3-60 Letter to The Director of Industries, Old Custom House Yard, 1960; 3.38.13
    - 27-2-60 Letter to Reprsentative of AITUC, 1960; 3.38.14
    - 4-3-60 Letter to The Labour Commissiner, Govt. of Madhya Pradesh, 1960; 3.38.15
  - Meeting of G.C. (circulars)
    Papers and minutes related to the AITUC General Council meeting of January 1960 and 1961; Circular for the 26th session of the AITUC held in Coimbatore, 1961; K. Ananda Nambiar letter to AITUC General Secretary.
    - 12-11-60 Letter to All Members of the General Council of the AITUC, 1960; 3.17.1
    - 10-10-60 Circular to all Affiliated Unions, 1960; 3.17.2
    - 29-7-60 Letter to The General Secretary, AITUC, 1960; 3.17.3
    - 13to16-2-60 Minutes of the AITUC General Council Meeting, 1960; 3.17.4
    - 14-1-60 Letter to All Members of the General Council, 1960; 3.17.5
    - Note-For attention of Members of the General Council, 1960; 3.17.6
    - Letter to AITUC, 1960; 3.17.7
  - General Council Meeting
    Attendance chart general council meeting of Coimbatore; Minutes of the AITUC general council meeting at Delhi 1960; Report on the work of AITUC Centre; Report on the organisational position and work of the AITUC in various States and Industries; Dange's speech on Organisational work; Report on textile and cement wage boards; Resolutions adopted by the general council of AITUC.
    - 3-1-60 Attendence Chart, G.C. Meeting, 1960; 3.16.1
    - 13to16-2-60 Minutes of the AITUC G.C. Meeting, 1960; 3.16.2
    - 13 to 15-2-60 Working Committee Attendence Chart, 1960; 3.16.3
    - Report on Work of AITUC Centre, 1960; 3.16.4
    - 1-2-60 The Orgnisational Position and Work of the AITUC in the Various States & Industries, 1960; 3.16.5
      English; Bangalore
    - Jobs Arising from G.C. Meeting, 1960; 3.16.6
    - Feb.& March-60 On organisational Work, Points from Com. Dange Summing up Speech, 1960; 3.16.7
      English / Tamil; Coimbatore
    - Points related to verious sector, 1960; 3.16.8
    - 18-2-60 For Favour of Publication, For Verious Sector, 1960; 3.16.9
  - Monthly Report (State Committees)
    Monthly reports related to the work of AITUC in the Year 1960 from Gujarat, Bihar, Assam, Andhra Pradesh, Tamil Nadu, Punjab, Himanchal, Orissa, Madras, Uttar Pradesh, Madhya Pradesh, Karnatak and West Bengal; Memorandum of Settlement between the coffee curing workers and the management of coffee plantations firms based in Manglore
    - 14-4-60 Monthly Reports from - Gujrat, 1960; 3.37.1
      English / Gujrati; Gujrat
    - 14-4-60 Monthly Reports from - Bihar, 1960; 3.37.2
      English; Bihar
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Assam, 1960; 3.37.3
    - 14-4-60 Monthly Reports from - Andhra Pradesh, 1960; 3.37.4
    - 10-6-60 Monthly Reports from - Tamil Nadu, 1960; 3.37.5
      English / Tamil; Tamil Nad
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Punjab & Himachal, 1960; 3.37.6
      English; Punjab & Himachal
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Cuttack, 1960; 3.37.7
      English; Cuttack
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Punjab, 1960; 3.37.8
      English; Punjab
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Madras, 1960; 3.37.9
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Uttar Pardesh, 1960; 3.37.10
      English / Hindi; Uttar Pradesh
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Madhya Pradesh, 1960; 3.37.11
      English; Madhya Pradesh
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - Karnataka, 1960; 3.37.12
      English; Karnataka
    - 10-3-60 Monthly Reports from - West Bengal, 1960; 3.37.13
      English; West Bengal
  - AITUC Papers – Delhi Report; GC meeting Feb’60
    Correspondence between CPI Bombay branch and S.A. Dange; Strike diary of 1959; The organisational position and work of the AITUC in various states and Industries in 1960; Note on decisions of the 18th session of the standing labour committee. Summary of the draft praposal on labour policies and programmes for the Third Five Year Plan. Information Bulletin of Kerala State Council, CPI; Memorandum submitted to the Governor of Kerala by A.K. Gopalan regarding the situation in Travencore; Comparative study of results of mid-term elections in Kerala state, 1960.
    - 5-3-60 Letter to Dear B.C.Secretary, 1960; 3.18.1
      Hindi; Bombay
    - 25-1-60 letter to Mr. Shekh Kaka, 1960; 3.18.2
    - 14-2-60 Letter to Dear Com. Dange, 1960; 3.18.3
    - 13 to 15-2-60 strike Diary 1959, 1960; 3.18.4
    - 1-2-60 The Organisational Position and Work of the AITUC in the various States & Industries, 1960; 3.18.5
    - 20-1-60 A Note on Decisions of the 18th Session of the Standing Labour Committee, 1960; 3.18.6
    - Draft proposals Policies & Programmes 3rd Five Year Plan, Part-I&II, 1960; 3.18.7
    - 15-2-60 Information Bullettin, Kerala State Council, 1960; 3.18.8
      English; Trivandrum
    - 14-2-60 Memorandum Submited to the Governor, 1960; 3.18.9
    - 1-2-60 Mid Term Elections Kerala State, 1960; 3.18.10
      English; Kerala
    - 10-2-60 Statement referred to in reply to parts (Lok Sabha), 1960; 3.18.11
  - G. Council meet circulars
    Circular issued by S.A. Dange, General Secretary of AITUC regading the working committee and general council meetings in Ernakulam.
    - 26-11-1957 To, The Secretaries - PTUCsCircular No. PTUC/D-1/57, 3.272.1
- Working Committee (AITUC), 1958-60
  - W.C. & G.C. (AITUC)
    Documents and Correspondence related to the general council session of the AITUC at Banglore, 1958; Documents and decisions related to the working committee meeting in Darjeeling, 1958; Report made by the AITUC related to inter-union relations; Papers of the 16th Indian Labour Conference; Report of the committees on Industrial relations, Social security, Subsidised industrial housing scheme.
    - Letters to Com. Dange, Srivastava on postcards, 1958; 4.32.1
      English; Indore, Darjeeling
    - 22-12-58 Letter to Comrade, 1958; 4.32.2
      English; Banglore
    - 19-12-58 Letter to Secretary, 1958; 4.32.3
    - 18-12-58 Com. Suryanarayana Rao, 1958; 4.32.4
    - 15-12-58 Letter to Secretary, 1958; 4.32.5
    - 9-12-58 Com. S.Suryanarayana Rao, 1958; 4.32.6
    - 6-12-58 GC, Letter to Sec., 1958; 4.32.7
    - An Appeal from Reception Committee, 1958; 4.32.8
    - 16-12-58 Com. Joglekar, 1958; 4.32.9
    - 16-12-58 Letter to All Members of the WC, 1958; 4.32.10
    - 16-12-58 GC meeting at Banglore, 1958; 4.32.11
    - 9-12-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.12
    - 27-11-58 Letter from K.G. Sriwastava, 1958; 4.32.13
    - 26-11-58 Reports of GC, 1958; 4.32.14
    - 20-11-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.15
    - 20-11-58 Telegram Reminder, 1958; 4.32.16
    - 17-11-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.17
    - 16-11-58 Letter to Gen. Sec., 1958; 4.32.18
      English; Karnatak
    - 16-11-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.19
    - 10-6-58 Decisions of the WC Meeting, Darjeeling, 1958; 4.32.20
    - 13-5-58 Ref No. TU/2/1/58/222, Chia Kaman Mazdur Union, 1958; 4.32.21
    - Suggestions made by AITUC Regarding Inter-Union Relations, 1958; 4.32.22
    - Decisions of the Informal Meeting of Central TU Org., 1958; 4.32.23
    - Papers Relating to 16th Indian Labour Conference, 1958; 4.32.24
    - 29-5-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.25
      English; Combatore
    - 23-5-58 Letter to Com. Ratanlal, 1958; 4.32.26
    - 25-5-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.27
    - 13-5-58 S.K. Bedi & Tobacco Labour Union, 1958; 4.32.28
      English; Manglore
    - 13-5-58 Latha Niwas, 1958; 4.32.29
      English; Trivanderum
    - 19-5-58 Letter to Com. Biren Bose, 1958; 4.32.30
    - 19-5-58 Letter to Com. Monoranjan Roy, 1958; 4.32.31
    - 14-5-58 Letter to Srivastava, 1958; 4.32.32
    - 9-5-58 SS Mirajkar, Letter to Com. Joglekar, 1958; 4.32.33
    - 8-5-58 SS Mirajkar, Letter to Com. Ratanlal, 1958; 4.32.34
    - 6-5-58 SS Mirajkar, Letter to Com. Monoranjan Roy, 1958; 4.32.35
    - 5-5-58 SS Mirajkar, Letter to Mirajkar, 1958; 4.32.36
    - 30-4-58 Letter to Dange, 1958; 4.32.37
    - 24-4-58 Letter to Mem. of WC, 1958; 4.32.38
    - 1-5-58 Ref. No. TU/2/1/58/189 Letter to Dange, 1958; 4.32.39
    - 1-5-58 Letter to Com. Dange, 1958; 4.32.40
    - 30-4-58 Ref.No. PTUC-AITUC/58-23 Letter to Sec, 1958; 4.32.41
    - 29-4-58 J.K. Ghose BSc, 1958; 4.32.42
    - 24-4-58 Telegram, 1958; 4.32.43
    - 24-4-58 SS Mirjakar, letter to Com. Ratanlal Brahman, 1958; 4.32.44
  - WC Meetings of AITUC